{"name": "52C  1996", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The greatest common divisor of 84, 90, and 66 (that is, the largest exact divisor of all three numbers) is:", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "12", "C": "18", "D": "36", "E": "90"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. If a circle's diameter is 5 meters, what is that circle's radius, in meters?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "5", "C": "", "D": "5\u03c0", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. If you've traveled x miles per hour for 3 hours, how many miles have you traveled?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "3x", "D": "60x", "E": "180x"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. (2ab2)3(3a2b)2 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "6a5b7", "B": "6a12b12", "C": "36a7b7", "D": " 72a7b8", "E": " 65a12b12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. in the figure below\uff0cwhat is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "5\u00b0", "B": "30\u00b0", "C": " 40\u00b0", "D": " 55\u00b0", "E": "60\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the solution value of x for the equation 3(x - 2) = 9x - 5 ?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "1"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. An architect is drawing scaled of apartment building that is to be 150 feet wide and 200 feet long. On the drawing, if the building is 48 inches long, how many inches wide should it be?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "16", "C": "", "D": "36", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. What is the 7th term in this sequence of \"triangular\" numbers, defined by the figures below: 1, 3, 6, 10, ...?", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "22", "C": "25", "D": "28", "E": "40"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. One angle,\u2220A, has 3 times the measure of its supplement, \u2220B, as depicted below. What is the degree measure of \u2220A?", "choices": {"A": "\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "135\u00b0", "D": "150\u00b0", "E": "\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. A weight lifter can lift 510 pounds. His goal is to improve by 20% during the next year. How many pounds does he want to be able to lift I year from now?", "choices": {"A": "512", "B": "530", "C": "602", "D": "610", "E": "612"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. If x = 4 and y = 5, what is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": "92", "B": "-70", "C": "-92", "D": "-100", "E": "-368"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. If a bag contains 5 blue marbles, 4 red marbles, and 3 green marbles, what is the probability that a marble randomly picked from the bag will be red?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. what is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. If m = 4, n = -3, and p = 2, what is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": "-0.50", "B": "-0.25", "C": "0.40", "D": "1.25", "E": "2.50"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. In \u25b3ABC below, the measures of \u2220A and \u2220C are each 45\u00b0, and AC is  centimeters (cm) long. How long, in centimeters, is AB ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. For all x and y, what is the sum of 2x2y - 3xy2 and -3x2y + 2xy2 ?", "choices": {"A": "x2y + xy2", "B": "x2y - xy2", "C": "-x2y - xy2", "D": "-x2y + xy2", "E": "-x4y2 - x2y4"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. What is the area, in square inches, of a triangle with a  height of 3 inches and a base 1 inch long?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. In the figure below, AB is parallel to CD. What is the  measure of \u2220ADC ?", "choices": {"A": "35\u00b0", "B": "40\u00b0", "C": "45\u00b0", "D": "65\u00b0", "E": "80\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. lf kx + k = 0, and k &gt; 1, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "-1", "C": "1", "D": "-k", "E": "k"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. \"Snake-eyes\" occur when you roll two 1's on a pair of  regular, 6-sided dice numbered from 1 to 6. On  any  roll, what is the  probability of rolling  snake-eyes?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Which of the following is a simplified form of 3x - (3 - x) + 1 ?", "choices": {"A": "2x - 2", "B": "2x + 2", "C": "2x + 4 ", "D": "4x - 2", "E": "4x + 4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. If |2x - 2| = 4, which of the following is a possible value for x?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "-1", "C": "0", "D": "1", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Lola is making the circle graph below showing the number of students at each grade level in her high school. What should be the measure of\u2220\u03b1 ?", "choices": {"A": "99\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "133\u00b0", "D": "167\u00b0", "E": "240\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. What point on the graph of x2 + y = 7 has an x-coordinate of -2?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "(-2, 3)", "C": "(-2, 5)", "D": "(-2, 9)", "E": "(-2, 11)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. What is the slope-intercept form of the equation 6x - 3y = 7 ?", "choices": {"A": "y = 2x - 7 ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": "y = 2x + 7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. A line segment with length of units is located on a 2 number line with 1 endpoint fixed at coordinate . What are the 2 possible coordinate locations of the other endpoint?", "choices": {"A": "9 and -2", "B": "9 and -9", "C": "2 and -8", "D": "2 and -9", "E": "2 and 9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. At a certain store, all radios are discounted to 15% less than the radio's regular price. A customer brings a radio marked with regular price of $120 to the a checkout counter. If a sales tax of 5% of the purchase price is added (rounded to the nearest cent), how much money does the customer owe?", "choices": {"A": "$102.90", "B": "$107.10", "C": "$108.00", "D": "$110.00", "E": "$110.25"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Distances marked on the figure below are in feet. Points B, E, F, and C are collinear as are points A, H, G, and D. If the area of rectangle ABCD is 33 square feet and EH and FG are each perpendicular to AD, what is the area, in square feet, of trapezoid AEFD?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "21", "C": "24", "D": "27", "E": "48"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In right triangle \u25b3ABC below, what is the value of sinA ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. In right triangle \u25b3ABC below, distances are shown in meters. How many meters long is AB ?", "choices": {"A": " 10", "B": "", "C": "5", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. On Family Day, attendance at the baseball game set a record. A reporter for the local paper asked how many adults had paid to see the game. The box office reported that exactly 450 tickets had been sold, and $2,000 was collected. If adults' tickets were $5 and children's tickets were $3, how many adults' tickets were sold?", "choices": {"A": "75", "B": "125", "C": "325", "D": "375", "E": "400"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. In the right triangle below, how many meters long is AB?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "7", "C": "5", "D": "3", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. The 2 triangles below are similar, with \u2220A \u2245 \u2220D. What is the perimeter of \u25b3DEF ?", "choices": {"A": "14", "B": "21", "C": "29", "D": "35", "E": "41"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. What is the  area, in  square units, of the graphed below?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "18", "C": "24", "D": "27", "E": "33"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. When graphed in the (x, y)coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line ?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "1", "E": "2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36.  Three-ring notebooks are made in 2 steps: Machine A makes 180 covers per hour. Later, Machine B attaches the 3-ring paper holder and completes 150 notebooks per hour. How many hours should Machine A run in order to produce the right number of covers for Machine B to finish in exactly8 hours of its operation?", "choices": {"A": " 5", "B": " ", "C": " 6", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. If the triangles in the figure below are similar, then \u03b1 = ?", "choices": {"A": "38\u00b0", "B": "46\u00b0", "C": "50\u00b0", "D": "65\u00b0", "E": "84\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Which of the following equations is graphed below?", "choices": {"A": "y = -3x", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": "y = 3x", "E": "y = x - 3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. What is the radius, in meters, of a circle if its circumference is 36\u03c0 meters?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "12", "C": "18", "D": "36", "E": "72"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Whenever x and z are nonzero numbers,  simplifies to:", "choices": {"A": "x-4z2", "B": "x-4z", "C": "x-4z-1", "D": "z2", "E": "z"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. In right triangle \u25b3ABC below, AB = 6, BC = 8, and AC = 10. Triangle \u25b3DEF was formed by connecting the midpoints of the sides of \u25b3ABC. What is the area of \u25b3DEF, in square units?(Note: The notation AB represents the length of the line segment AB.)", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "10", "C": "12", "D": "18", "E": "24"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Three times a year a camera shop has a sale on packages of batteries: in February packages are 3 for $4.49, in April they are 5 for $7.39, and in December they are 4 for $5.88. In which ordered sequence of months does the price per package go from smallest to middle to largest?", "choices": {"A": "February, December, April ", "B": "April, February, December", "C": "April, December, February", "D": "December, February, April ", "E": "December, April, February"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The trinomial x2 - x - 6 can be factored as the product of 2 linear factors, in the form (x + a)(x + b). What is the polynomial sum of these 2 factors?", "choices": {"A": "2x - 1", "B": "2x + 1", "C": "2x - 5", "D": "2x + 5", "E": "2x - 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. A rectangular field is twice as long as it is wide, and has an area of 288 square meters. How many meters long is it?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "24", "C": "36", "D": "72", "E": "144"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. If , then x - y = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. If the total surface area, A, of a cylinder (including its ends) is given by the formula A = 2\u03c0r2 + 2\u03c0rh, which of the following expresses h in terms of A and r?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " h = 2\u03c0rA - r", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. If , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. From a point on the ground the angle of elevation to a ledge on a building is 27\u00b0, and the distance to the base of the building is 45 meters. How many meters high is the ledge?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "45 sin27\u00b0", "D": "45 cos27\u00b0", "E": "45 tan27\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. In the standard(x, y) coordinate plane there is only one circle centered at the point (-1, 4) that also passes through the point (7, -2) Which of the following is an equation for that circle?", "choices": {"A": "(x + 1)2 + (y - 4)2 = 10", "B": "(x + 1)2 + (y - 4)2 = 100", "C": "(x - 1)2 + (y - 4)2 = 100", "D": "(x - 4)2 + (y + 1)2 = 100", "E": "(x - 4)2 + (y + 1)2 = 10"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. If a is any real number, for what real value(s) of b does the equation |x + a| = b have NO solutions for x?", "choices": {"A": "All b &lt; 0 ", "B": "Only b = -1", "C": "Only b = 0 ", "D": "All b \u2260 0", "E": "AlI b &gt; 0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Which of the following is closest to 5 \u00d7 104 ?", "choices": {"A": "1, 000", "B": "5, 000", "C": "100, 000", "D": "500, 000", "E": "6, 250, 000"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Which of the following is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "sec2\ud835\udfb1", "B": "(csc2\ud835\udfb1) - 1", "C": " tan2\ud835\udfb1", "D": "sin2\ud835\udfb1", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. To work properly, an engine part's diameter cannot be over the specified diameter of 3 centimeters by more than .05 centimeters, nor can it be under the specified diameter by more than .05 centimeters. If x is the diameter of a part, which of the following algebraic statements specifies these restrictions on x?", "choices": {"A": "x - 3  \u2265 .05", "B": "3 - x   \u2265 .05", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. For all a \u2260 0; what is the slope of the line segment connecting (a, b) and (-a, b) in the usua| (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2a"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Starting at her doorstep, Ramona walked down the sidewalk at 1.5 feet per second for 4 seconds. Then she stopped for 4 seconds, realizing that she had forgotten something. Next she returned to her doorstep along the same route at 1.5 feet per second. The graph of Ramona's distance (d) from her doorstep as a function of time (t) would most resemble which of the following ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. For the quadratic equation 2x2 + 5x + R = 0, what value of R will make the solutions for x be  and -3 ?", "choices": {"A": "27", "B": "3", "C": "2", "D": "", "E": "-3"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. If A is the measure of an acute angle (that is, 0\u00b0 \uff1c A \uff1c 90\u00b0) and sin A =, what are the possible values of tan A ?", "choices": {"A": "and", "B": "and", "C": "only", "D": "only", "E": "only"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. If , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "8", "E": "10"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. If f(x) = 3x3 - 27x, which of the following correctly describes the zeros of the polynomial ?(Note: Zeros are values of x where f(x) = 0)", "choices": {"A": "No real zeros", "B": "Only 1 rational zero", "C": "Only 1 real zero, which is irrational", "D": "1 number is a double zero", "E": "3 different rational zeros"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Given 9 points, NO 3 of which lie on the same straight line, what is the maximum number of straight lines that can be drawn through pairs of those 9 points ?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "9", "C": "27", "D": "36", "E": "72"}, "correct": "D"}]}